Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Records 1972.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series I: An Inventory, 1882, 1888-1920, 1924, 1933-1947; 22.05 Linear feet
  - Correspondence, notes, photographs, financial records, preliminary sketches, postcards, 1888-1890, 1892-1907, 1910-1914, 1916, 1918, 1920; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, alphabetized P-V (Box 9)
    [Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Prof. L.A. Clinton; The Agricultural Experts Association; George T. Powell; Plimpton Manufacturing Co., Envelope and Blank Book Manufacturers; Frank S. Platt Co., Growers and Dealers in Lima Beans, Garden, Field, and Flower Seeds; U.S. Envelope Co.; Q and C Co.; Prof. W.O. Atwater; Wesleyan University; Prof. C.S. Phelps; W.H. Latham & Co., Builders; Peter Hendersen Seed Co.; Norwich, Conn. School; Bridgeport Deoxidized Bronze and Metal Co.; O.H. Platt, Senator; Pound-a-Minute Churn Company; Maple Grove Farm; Lucien Sanderson, Importer of Agricultural Chemicals; Connecticut Dairymen's Association; The Evening Post Editorial Department; James S. Ray, Manufacturer of Casket Hardware; Forbes Diastase Company; The Electrominus Company; New Jersey State Board of Agriculture; Republic of Hawaii (1899); "Porto Rico"; B.B. Noyes & Co.; University of Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station; Dr. Conn; Rhode Island Agricultural Experiment Station; Peck, Stow, and Wilcox Co., Tinners, Machines, and Tools; Escuela Nacional De Agricultura y Veterinaria (Peru); Arthur W. Dox.
    Agricultural subjects addressed in correspondence: alfalfa cultivation, entomology, seed corn ("leaning" and "pride of the north"); dairy; bovine tuberculosis; bacteria.
    Assorted non-correspondence items: Photographs (Storrs Agricultural School barns); Preliminary sketches for planning a newly-invented butter churn.
    Agricultural colleges--Photographs.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Agriculture--Connecticut.; Agriculture--Study and teaching.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)--Education Universities and Colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)--Science and scientific affairs--Research institutes.; Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; Storrs (Conn.)—Buildings, structures, etc.; University of Connecticut--History.
  - Correspondence, clippings, ephemera, postcards, financial records, 1894, 1902, 1904-1920; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, alphabetized O-S (Box 10)
    [Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Orange Judd Co., Publishers and Importers of all Standard Books Pertaining to Rural Affairs; The Canadian Horticulturalist; The Rural New Yorker; The Hartford Evening Post; Iowa Experiment Station; Ginn & Co., Publishers of School and College Text-books; The Technical World Magazine, Chicago; C.D. Jarvis; Prof. L.A. Clinton; The London Times, American Office; Success Magazine: A Periodical of American Life; Purdue University Agricultural Experiment Station; Central Vermont Railroad; Quinebaug Pomona Grange; The Riggs School, Inc.; The Rugg & Faber Co.; The Shaw-Walker Co., Muskegon, Michigan; Columbia University, Department of Chemistry; Prof. W.O. Atwater; Stanley and Patterson, Inc., Manufacturer of General Electrical Equipment Supplies; R.W. Stimson; W.O. Stocking, Jr.; Russ Bro's [sic] Co., Farm Machinery and Fertilizers; Remington Typewriter Co.; Richardson Manufacturing Co.; Roethlisberger & Co.; H.G. Rampsberger & Co.; The Springfield Republican.
    Agricultural subjects addressed in correspondence include: production of camembert and roquefort cheese.
    Publications and ephemera: clipping of article "Common Weed Pests," by Dr. L.H. Pammel, Iowa Experiment Station; schedule of events for the "Second Annual Meeting of the National Association of Dairy Instructors and Investigators, Chicago, October 11, 12, 1907 (ephemera).
    General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, University of Connecticut History, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Business.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Agriculture--Connecticut.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; University of Connecticut--History.
  - Correspondence, financial records, notes, ephemera, legal documents, 1888, 1894-1895, 1897, 1901-1902, 1904, 1906-1908, 1910-1920, 1941-1944; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, alphabetized R-V (Box 11)
    [Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Russian Department of Agriculture; W.A. Stocking, Jr.; E.A. Strout Farm Agency, Inc.; The Old Homestead Dairy and Poultry Farm; C.L. Beach; Edwin O. Smith; W.L. Slate; Duzer Du, Dramatic Fraternity, Defauw University, Greencastle, Indiana; Alphano Humus Company; Southern Pacific Railroad; Central Vermont Railroad; Samuel Cupples Envelope Co.; Sanderson Fertilizer Co.; Skinner Chuck Co.; Sturgis & Walton Co., Publishers; Tirrill Gas Machine Lighting Co.; Brown-Howland Co., Inc. of Connecticut; Underwood Typewriter Co.; U.S. Smelting Co.; S.L. Allen & Co; S.R. Feil Co.; W.O. Atwater; W.L. Slate; Dean E.G. Woodward; Big Y Laboratory; Dean W.B. Young; Pres. A.N. Jorgensen; State College of Washington, College of Agriculture and Agricultural Experiment Station; Smithsonian Institution; Society of Educational Extension; South African Government Laboratory; R.W. Stimson; Underwood Travel System; L.A. Clinton; Virginia State Crop Pest Commission; War Manpower Commission.
    Agricultural Subjects discussed in correspondence include: plight of Russian peasantry (pre-revolution); Soil testing and crop fertilization; potato culture; swamp draining (to create farmland); Planet Jr. 12-toothed harrow (agricultural product produced by S.L. Allen & Co.); Sheep parasites (to be treated with medicated salt); Shropshire sheep; Lime-tree winter-moth; Bordeaux mixture (pesticide); bean weevil.
    General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural College, Connecticut Agricultural College, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, University of Connecticut History.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Agriculture--Connecticut.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.; Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; Storrs (Conn.)—Education—Universities and colleges.; University of Connecticut--History.; University of Connecticut.
  - Correspondence, legal documents, notes, postcards, publications, 1889-1890, 1892-1920; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, alphabetized V-Z (Box 12)
    [Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute; Van Ogden Voght; John H. Voorhees; North Jersey Society for the Promotion of Agriculture; United States Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations; Farmers' Institute Movement; C.F. Doane; Arthur W. Dox; Dr. D.E. Salmon; E.H. Webster; Charles M. Jarvis; C.B. Lane; L.A. Clinton; G.M. Rommel, Animal Husbandman; War Department, Surgeon General's Office, U.S. Army Medical Museum and Library (1889); Prof. W.O. Atwater; Signal Service, U.S. Army; Smithsonian Institution; United States Department of Agriculture Weather Bureau; World's Columbian Exposition (1892); Dir. A.W. Harris, Office of Experiment Stations, USDA; E.W. Allen, Office of Experiment Stations, USDA; Department of Labor; Department of the Interior, Department of Pensions (1902); Hon. N.D. Sperry, House of Representatives; United States Department of Agriculture, division of Agrostology; Hon. O.H. Platt; Gov. O. Vincent Coffin; Dir. A.C. True; Hon. Watson C. Squire, Senator; Hon. Martin A. Knapp; Sen. E.S. Henry; Hon. Joseph R. Hawley; University of Chicago; Susan B. Sipe; Earl Bixby Ferson; University of Florida, Florida Experiment Station; Pres. Andrew Sledd, University of Illinois College of Agriculture Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Maine, Prof. W.D. Hurd; University of Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station; Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station; Wesleyan University; Worcester County Horticultural Society.
    Agricultural subjects discussed in correspondence include: Poultry farming; Camembert and Rocquefort cheese; Dairy goats (known as "Milch Goats"); Maltese Goats; Maltese (or Malta) Fever; Cultivation of plants in sand and water (plant cultivation exhibit for World's Fair); law against oleomargarine; army worms (pests); alfalfa cultivation; San Jose scale insects (pests); Bordeaux Mixture (pesticide); asparagus cultivation; Oyster Shell Scale insects (pests).
    Publications and other non-correspondence items: "Bulletin of the New England Weather Service, November 1895, No. 45" (Publication); USDA Office of the Secretary: Regulations Governing Appointments to Positions of Expert and Agent in the Department of Agriculture (legal documents).
    General Subjects: United States Deparment of Agriculture; Storrs Agricultural School; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Connecticut History.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Agriculture--Study and teaching.; Agriculture—Connecticut.; Connecticut—Agriculture.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; University of Connecticut--History.; University of Connecticut.
  - Correspondence, financial records, ephemera, 1888-1889, 1891-1903, 1905, 1908, 1913-1915, 1919-1920, 1933-1947; 1.3 Linear feet Folders, Alphabetized W-Z (Box 13)
    [Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: Prof. W.L. Slate; New England Corn Exposition; H.C. Wells; H.R. Watts; Pres. C.L. Beach; Winship Teachers' Agency; The Vermont Farm Machine Co., Manufacturers the Improved U.S. Cream Separators and Dairy Specialties; Nathan G. Williams; C.D. Jarvis; M.H. Williams, Grower and Breeder of Yellow Dent Seed Corn, "The Kind that Matures;" Albida Farm, A.A. Wigand, Niantic, Connecticut; West Virginia University; Wyoming State Board of Agriculture; Williams Patent Crusher and Pulverizer, Inc.; Atlanta Milling Co.; White Adding Machine Co.; Charles Warner Co.; Dean W.B. Young; United States Department of Agriculture; A.N. Jorgensen; Dir. C.E.F. Goterman, Cornell Agricultural Experiment Station; J.H. Washburn, Wemanesa Grange no. 170; Weston Electrical Instrument Co.; Prof. Francis G. Benedict; C.D. Woods; W.O. Atwater; Wesleyan University Chemical Laboratory; New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station; Prof. E.B. Voorhees; American Cereal Co.; Pennsylvania State College; University of Vermont; H.C. Humphrey, American Glucose Co.; New York Agricultural Experiment Station; Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station.
    Agricultural Subjects discussed in correspondence: potato grubs; field plowing; alfalfa cultivation; Bordeaux Mixture (pesticide); Potato Blight; sowing hay; ground moles (and how to trap them); crushed lime vs. caustic lime (fertilizers); usage of the "bomb calorimeter" for digestion and metabolic experiments; 1892 Cholera scare in Storrs; Sheep feeding experiments; dietary research; respiraton calorimeter.
    General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Correspondence, United States Deparment of Agriculture, University of Connecticut History.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Agriculture--Connecticut.; Connecticut—Agriculture.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; University of Connecticut--History.; University of Connecticut.
  - Correspondence, notes, publications, administrative records, legal documents, 1888, 1892-1899, 1901-1902, 1937-1941; 1.3 Linear feet Folders (Box 14)
    [Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: State of Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station; Oklahoma Department of Agriculture; Rural Publishing Co.; Rhode Island Board of Agriculture; New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station; Dr. C.D. Woods; Pennsylvania State College; Association of American Agricultural Colleges and Experiment Stations; Hon. Edward Atkinson; Pratt Institute, Brooklyn; New England Homestead / The New York Homestead; New Hampshire College of Agriculture and the Mechanic Arts; West Virginia University and Agricultural Experiment Station; Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Minnesota Agricultural Experiment Station; Maine State College Agricultural Experiment Station; H.P. Armsby, Committee on Agricultural Experiment Station Exhibit at World's Fair; Agricultural Department, State of Florida; F.G. Benedict; State Library of Massachusetts; A.O. Bryant; Iowa Agricultural Experiment Station; University of Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station; Michigan Agricultural College; St. Louis & Hannibal Railway, Missouri; W.O. Atwater; Maine State College Agricultural Experiment Station; American Jersey Cattle Club; J.J. Hemingway; Alabama Agricultural College; Wesleyan University Chemical Laboratory; Leuthi Bros., Gnadenhutten, Ohio; Florida Agricultural Department; The Rural New Yorker; New Hampshire College; World's Columbian Commission; C.D. Woods; Harry C. Flood; Schuyler Electric Co.; Pennsylvania State College Agricultural Experiment Station; Rhode Island State Board of Agriculture; Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station; Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station; North Carolina Agricultural Experiment Station; Vermont Experiment Station; University of Arizona Agricultural Experiment Station; W.L. Slate; United States Department of Agriculture; C.B. Gentry.
    Non-correspondence documents include: "The Logarty Gas & Chemical Co.: Ammonia from the Nitrogen of the Air, November 1894 (publication);" Personal Affadavits (legal declarations of anti-communist, anti-fascist, and anti-Nazi affiliation).
    General subjects: Agricultural Experiment Stations, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural College, University of Connecticut History, University of Connecticut in World War II.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Agriculture—Connecticut.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.; Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; University of Connecticut--History.; University of Connecticut.
  - Correspondence, financial records, notes, 1882, 1886-1889, 1895-1896, 1898-1901, 1903-1905; 1.3 Linear feet Folders (Box 15)
    [Subjects include: Bills and Receipts from assorted businesses: Lucius R. Hazen, Bookseller, Stationer, and Newsdealer; Bausch & Lomb Optical Co.; Wesleyan University Chemical Laboratory; Scribner and Welford, Importers of Books; Educational Supply Co.; Eimer & Amend, importers of Chemicals and Chemical Apparatus; Remington Standard Typewriter; J.P. Barstow & Co.; N.A. Stearns & Son, Manufacturers and Dealers in Harness, Robes, Blankets, Brushes, Whips, etc.; Mapes Formula and Peruvian Guano Co.; Southern New England Telephone Co.; Aero Distilled Water Co.; American Electrical Works; Baker & Adamson Chemical Co; Beach & Co.; A. Brazos & Sons; Bugbee Bros.; Baker & Co.; F.B. Fargo & Co.; Hall & Bill Printing Co.; S.S. White Dental Manufacturing Co.
    Payment to, and bills from, individuals: W.E. Foster, C.S. Phelps (charging for travel expenses), W.O. Atwater, A.W. Stocking, F.G. Benedict, H.E. Bidwell, Albert Bingham, C.S. Blakeslee, Revella Bognini, Oscar Bowers, John Bowman, James H. Bunce, G.R. Burdick, M.A. Bates, Arthur F. Green, W.N. Hill, William F. House, G.H. Hulbert, Jr, R.E. Turner, F.A. Bagnoll.
    Correspondence from W.O. Atwater.
    General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural College, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Financial Records, University of Connecticut History.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Agriculture--Connecticut.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.; Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; Storrs, Conn.; University of Connecticut--History.; University of Connecticut.
  - Correspondence, publications, postcards, legal documents, financial records, 1888, 1892-1901; 1.3 Linear feet Folders (Box 16)
    [Subjects include: Correspondence to and from: W.O. Atwater; Remington Standard Typewriter; Eimer & Amend, Importers of Chemicals and Chemical Apparatus; Pelton & King; Lucius R. Hazen, Bookseller and Stationer; Gustav E. Stechert, Importer of Books and Periodicals; John P. Barstow & Co., Dealers in Stoves, Furnaces, Ranges, Farming Implements, Seeds, and Fertilizers; New York City Custom House; Case Lockwood & Brainard Co.; Mapes Formula and Peruvian Guano Co.; Peabody Museum of American Archaeology and Ethnology (Harvard); Gustav E. Stechert, Importer of Books and Periodicals; The German Kali Works; Gilbert & Barnes Manufacturing Co.; Fairbanks, Brown, & Co. Standard Scales; Middletown Gas Light Co.; Bailey Manufacturing Co., Manufacturer of Bailey's Letter-copying Machine; C.D. Woods, Wesleyan University; Felt & Tarrant Manufacturing Co.; Aero Distilled Water Co.; G.W. Sheldon & Co.
    Non-correspondence documents include: "Schedules for Financial Reports of the Agricultural Experiment Stations as prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture" (periodically published books intended for use in recording financial records; mostly unused, from years 1896 and 1897); "Illustrated Price List of Hoskins' Patent Hydro-Carbon Blow-Pipe and Furnaces" (publication or flier--intended as advertising).
    General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station financial records and corresponence, Storrs Agricultural College, University of Connecticut history.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Agriculture--Connecticut.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.; Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; Storrs, Conn.; University of Connecticut--History.
  - Books (3) (ledgers), financial records, notes, 1889-1892, 1893-1894, 1897-1899; 0.25 Linear feet Books (ledgers), numbered 56-58 (Box 17)
    [Subjects include: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Ledgers numbered 56, 57, and 58, covering monetary exchanges over the dates April-December 1889, January-December 1890, January-December 1892, January-December 1893, January-June 1897, July-December 1897, January-December 1898, January-June 1899.
    Names included in ledger notes: W.O. Atwater, C.S. Phelps, C.L. Beach, B.F. Koons.
    General Subjects: Storrs Agricultural College, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Financial Records.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Financial Records.; Ledgers.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.; Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; University of Connecticut--History.
  - Books (4) (ledgers), financial records, 1896-1904; 1.0 Linear feet Books (ledgers), numbered 53-55, 59 (Box 18)
    [Subjects include: Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station Ledgers, numbered 53, 54, 55 and 59, covering monetary transactions over the dates June-December 1896, January-June 1897, July-December 1897, January-December 1898, January-June 1899 and the years 1899-1904.
    Names included in ledgers: W.O. Atwater (Erroneously called "O.W. Atwater"), Charles Lewis Beach.
    General subjects: Storrs Agricultural School, Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Financial Records.
    Agricultural colleges—Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges—Connecticut—History.; Agricultural experiment stations—Connecticut.; Financial Records.; Ledgers.; Storrs (Conn.); Storrs (Conn.)-- Education.; Storrs (Conn.)—Agriculture.; University of Connecticut--History.